{
    "id": "9ceb81ebce7441d591a2b6643ecf21e3",
    "title": "English Vocabulary Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Meera was extremely angry but I …………………… her by promising to leave her house and never return.",
            "description": "To assuage is to soothe or pacify.",
            "answers": [
                "assuaged",
                "persuaded",
                "coerced"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "More research needs to be done in how to …………………… conservation needs with growing demand for natural resources.",
            "description": " To reconcile something with something is to find ways to make them both capable of existing together. ",
            "answers": [
                "align",
                "reconcile",
                "oblige"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… by her friends, she lost all hope.",
            "description": "To forsake somebody is to leave them when they still need you.",
            "answers": [
                "Forbidden",
                "Forsaken",
                "Forlorn"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A ………………….. study found the site suitable for building the airport.",
            "description": " Feasibility is the chances that something has of becoming successful. A feasibility study is done to see if something is possible. ",
            "answers": [
                "viability",
                "feasibility",
                "economic"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "His party should be blamed for the political ……………………… in the country.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "stalemate",
                "revival",
                "devaluation",
                "advocacy"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Work on the project cannot start until the planning authority gives ………………………… to the development.",
            "description": "Consent is the permission to do something.",
            "answers": [
                "compliance",
                "consent",
                "projection"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We won`t be able to maintain our competitive advantage without …………………… this deal.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "culminating",
                "clinching",
                "canvassing",
                "crossing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A series of financial blunders ………………………. in the collapse of one of the largest banking institutions in the world.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "coincided",
                "coexisted",
                "culminated"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Man is ……………………… however, he needs mental companionship more than physical companionship.",
            "description": "Gregarious means sociable. Human beings are gregarious because they are fond of the company of others. ",
            "answers": [
                "egoistic",
                "altruistic",
                "gregarious"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie`s decision to marry her best friend`s ex-boyfriend left me …………………… I couldn`t figure out why she should want to do it.",
            "description": " To leave someone nonplussed is to perplex them.",
            "answers": [
                "exhausted",
                "demolished",
                "nonplussed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The journey took longer than we expected because the driver brought us by a …………………….. route.",
            "description": " A circuitous route is a roundabout route.",
            "answers": [
                "ambiguous",
                "circular",
                "circumscribed",
                "circuitous"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Students protested against school regulations that ………………. their social activities.",
            "description": " To circumscribe something is to limit it.",
            "answers": [
                "circumvented",
                "circumscribed",
                "circulated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}